Blood. Blood. Blood. And death.
All right. You know what?
You're milking it.
Besides, I think we got it.
We got it up there.
Thank you, Yakkity-yak.
You laid it all out beautifully.
I framed Lionheart. I can frame you too.
It's my word against yours.
Actually...
And I'll dart every predator in Zootopia
to keep it that way.
It's your word against yours.
It's called a hustle, sweetheart.
Boom.
Unlikely duo
Judy Hopps, the city's first bunny cop,
and Nicholas Wilde,
a small-time street fox,
uncovered a conspiracy
by Mayor Bellwether today
using a toy carrot recorder pen.
I can frame you too.
Wilde later joined the ZPD himself,
where the pair are now the very first
bunny-fox team
in the history of Zootopia.
New mayor and former actor
Brian Winddancer hailed the two
during celebrations
for the 100th anniversary
of the invention
of Zootopia's weather walls
that allowed all environments
and all animals
to coexist in one city.
This is our Zootennial!
And if a lowly country bunny
and a shifty, likely criminal fox
can ignore their vast, vast differences
and solve bias and stereotype forever,
then maybe we can all
embrace our differences
and be better zoogether.
We're gonna crack a new case,
make the world a better place,
and be the greatest partners of all time.
I mean, we're not that different.
At the ZPD, partnership is
the cornerstone of success.
You want to put bad guys away?
Be on the same page. Every day.
Now today's bad guy is
this customs inspector,
who's been smuggling
illegal overseas cargo
through the city's shipyard.
Captains Hoggbottom
and Truffler will lead.
Higgins, Bloats, flank left.
Chèvre, Bûcheron, right.
-And down the middle, the Zebros.
-Zebros!
Hopps and Wilde, I know you're eager
to prove yourselves,
but as rookies, you will observe only
and watch the veteran teams
show you how it's...
Chief, hi.
If you're looking for Nick and Judy,
they said they got it.
And they are already on site,
with their baby!
Are you sure this'll work?
You're the one that said we needed a bust.
Just follow my lead, okay? Act casual.
-Hey!
-Here we go.
Hello?
This whole area's restricted.
You can't be here.
Fox and bunny. Okay.
Yes, but proud parents first.
-Mister...
-Inspector.
Inspector Snootley.
Inspector? What do you do?
Ensure that nothing illegal gets smuggled
here in one of these cargo containers?
That's a weird way to ask that.
Anyway, you gotta leave.
You can't be here.
Wait. Wait.
He's right, gosh darn it.
You are right, sir.
I guess we should've thought this through.
Right, babe?
Before we decided to come down here
to this beautiful industrial shipyard
to celebrate the big day
of our birthday boy.
It's his birthday?
Yeah. First one since...
since the accident.
And, you know, the one thing
this little stinker wished for,
aside from one day
getting his tail reattached,
was to see a choo-choo.
And to maybe get a toot-toot conductor
to sign his cast.
But I'm betting a customs inspector
would be even better.
Really?
All right. For the kid. For the kid.
You're a saint.
We thank you so much.
Here you go. Either leg.
Or both. I don't care.
Maybe put a doodle on it.
Doesn't need to be perfect.
He's also legally blind.
I put a little train there
because I know you like trains.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
-Just jiggle it.
-Yes. I know.
-Hurry!
-I got this.
Jiggle it. Jiggle it. Jiggle it!
Hopps and Wilde, you are not authorized.
Stand down and wait for backup.
Toot, toot.
-It's the fuzz!
-Stop!
-Stop in the name of the law!
-Everybody run!
Well, can't win 'em all.
Get outta the road, you dumb bunny.
Agree to disagree.
My hog rod! This is a snoutrage!
Hopps and Wilde in pursuit of suspect
in a stolen catering van heading east...
Stop it.
...heading east through Sheepshire.
Beautiful.
I'll have what he's having.
Darling, I believe your driving is
giving me some white hairs.
Also, am I always gonna be
in the passenger's seat?
'Cause if we're establishing sides...
Back off, rookies!
Let the real teams handle it.
-Ma'am, we are a real team.
-Shortcut. Take the tunnel.
Stand down, noobs.
We got him.
-Rolling spikes!
I hate that dumb bunny.
-I'm gonna jump.
-What?
No, no. What are you...
Carrots, hey... I would like to call
a partner meeting. No, Carrots!
Judy!
Please join me in a moment of silence
for our beloved weather wall inventor
Ebenezer Lynxley.
Zebros!
Reptile?
Chief, those two are out of control!
Zootopia ain't just a mammal city.
It has a secret, tiny reptile population,
though most live abroad.
Of course, Zootopia does not allow snakes.
There ain't been one of those around here
for at least a hundred years.
"Scales and tales of the weird."
Yeah, not sure Nibbles Maplestick
is our most reliable source.
Bunny, orange dog, in here now.
Sir, today may not have been ideal,
but the anteater was captured.
By the Zebros!
-Zebros!
-Shut it!
Zebros.
It was us.
But more importantly, I believe we may
have made a significant discovery.
The stolen van contained a smuggled crate
from overseas,
pamphlets for the Zootennial,
and some type of reptile skin.
I've already sent samples for testing.
-And if you...
-What needs testing is you!
You two tore up half the city.
Because of you,
we had to call in Jumbo Unit
to remove a dik-dik from a tuba!
-You're almost out. You're gonna be...
-No! Please, no!
Who's catching him?
Sorry, could you show me that clip again?
Wasn't wearing my glasses.
Did you or did you not disobey
a direct order to stand down?
Sir, we were in pursuit.
And article 6, paragraph B states,
"If the lead officers think..."
You are not lead officers!
You're one-hit wonders
who should go back to meter maiding
and slinging pawpsicles!
If I may, I think someone's just jealous
that we got to drive the squeal mobile.
Or maybe you thought it was your momma.
Enough! Everybody out.
Officer Hopps,
despite my best efforts to avoid it,
I like you.
But this need to overdo it
made both of you a headline today.
And it reflects badly on me,
on the department,
and frankly on any bunny hoping
to follow in your footsteps.
Not every case is going to save the world.
Knock-knock.
Hi.
You know, this kinda... this sounds a lot
like a... just a "you guys" conversation.
So what I'm gonna do
is I'm gonna go ahead and...
Is there a reason why you don't
take anything seriously?
Jokes are a classic defense mechanism
for someone with a traumatic childhood.
Would you like a traumatic adulthood?
I would not.
I allowed you to work together
because you did this city a great service.
But today, you messed it all up.
And now,
some are questioning whether you should've
been partners in the first place.
-Sir...
-So,
instead of chasing imaginary reptiles,
I am pulling you from the field...
-What?
-...and giving you a new assignment
reserved for special teams
like yourselves.
Fail at this, and I will have no choice
but to split you up.
There will be no more Hopps and Wilde.
But if you're as good
as you think you are,
this is your moment to shine.
Welcome to Partners in Crisis,
a workshop for duos heading for disaster.
I'm your therapy animal, Dr. Fuzzby.
And you are here
because mismatched pairings
often need a little more work
to make them work.
Greg, we talked about that.
What are we making Marlon?
Uncomfortable. Yes.
And, Francine, Clark may be a mouse,
but he is your partner first.
And we have two new "apart-ners."
Can you tell us about your journey
to dysfunction junction?
Well, we've been official partners
for one week.
Happy anniversary.
And we're not dysfunctional
at all, actually.
Functioning fine. Better than fine.
And we did sort of save the city,
so us being here kinda seems like
a huge misunderstanding.
Notice how she answered first,
did not allow her partner to speak,
seems to be in a state of denial
and taps her foot
when she's suppressing discomfort.
And observe the source of her discomfort
represented by
the disconnected affectation
of her emotionally insecure partner.
But with hard work,
they'll be on the same page by year two.
But for now,
let's begin by greeting our teammate.
Who'd like to go first?
Thank you, Joel.
Okay, unfortunately, Karen has chosen to
see Joel's smile as a sign of aggression.
Hackles down, Karen. Karen, hackles down.
Joel, the safe word is "coconut."
Coconut!
Okay, we have to set
another meeting with the Chief.
Promise we'll be better.
Zebros!
You talk back less. Maybe not at all.
Yeah. Or we go with my playbook,
and we just lay low.
We cannot prove ourselves
if we are stuck in that room.
And if we complain to Chief Beef,
he'll just make us stay longer.
Play it smart. Stay off the radar.
And don't let it get to you. Okay?
'Cause we are the dream team.
Sorry, Paul.
Roll out the red carpet.
Here's the super cops.
Hey, what does the fox say?
You suck!
Easy, partner.
Let me ask you something.
Do you think we're a good team?
Of course.
I just...
I just wish I knew what we had to do
to prove it to everyone else.
Or maybe we don't have
to prove anything to anybody.
We do. Forever.
And the sooner everyone sees
a fox and a bunny can be
great partners, the better. Enjoy it.
-I got two.
-I'd rather chew off my own arm.
Happy anniversary!
Coconut!
So, saw you were on TV. You okay?
Everything's fine, Mom.
Uh-oh. Everyone knows
"fine" is a cry for help.
You know who else cried for help?
That dik-dik stuck in that tuba.
Him and the dik-dik.
What does your fox partner say?
Well, Nick's not really a talker.
Well, you two are very different.
Small-town hero raised on a farm.
Big-city crook raised on the streets.
I pray every day that you'll come
back home and make babies.
Mom!
Just remember the first rule
of partnerships.
-You can be right or you can be happy.
-That's true.
There's nothing wrong
with dying a little inside
so you can meet in the middle.
-Honey, you're pushing me out.
-I wanna make sure I can be seen.
-Well, if she could see both of us.
-Gotta go. Work to do.
-Bye, bun-bun.
-Everything's gonna be fine.
-You two just need a new case.
-Got it. Love you.
-Maybe try to find that dik-dik.
-Bye.
Squeal of Fortune!
Tomorrow's weather is, again, everything.
...to announce that
the long-awaited Tundratown expansion
will be starting soon.
Residents continue to raise concerns
about the future of their neighborhood.
But tonight,
we put our differences aside
and celebrate at the Zootennial gala,
where the Lynxley Journal will be on
display for the first time in a century,
following an infamous reptile attack.
The Lynxley Journal, containing
the patented weather wall plans,
was originally written by
Ebenezer Lynxley, bringing...
Same catering company.
The Lynxley journal.
Truth bomb!
The 100th anniversary of the weather walls
is also the 100th anniversary
of Zootopia's only snake attack.
The victim? A tortoise.
The Lynxley family maid who was fanged
while stopping a venomous snake
from stealing the Lynxley Journal.
No one has seen a snake in Zootopia since.
But I'm convinced one will return.
My only question is,
is he gonna be wearing
half-a-pants or one long sock?
You say, "Justice is dead."
I say, "Neigh!"
Well, well, you miss me already, huh?
The stolen van with the snake skin is
from the same catering company
that's working the gala.
This is you studying your partner book?
Listen to me. Venomous snakes tried
to steal the Lynxleys's journal before.
What if they're back in town
to steal it again?
No snake has set foot in Zootopia
in forever, okay?
Even if they had feet.
Look, we're already in the hot seat,
Carrots, and pizza's here. Gotta go--
If there's a fanging at the gala
and we do nothing to stop it,
then we are not doing our jobs…
Yikes. No wonder you never invite me over.
Foxes are solitary.
And, look, we go and you're wrong,
Chief Beef will split us up.
And if we don't get a win soon
and prove we're great partners,
the chief will split us up anyway.
Check the perimeter. Snoop a little.
We find nothing, we bail.
But if I'm right, no one will question
whether you and I belong together again.
We need this.
Fine.
But we'll still have
to get through security,
and in fancy town,
a fox and a bunny won't exactly blend in.
That's why we'll be undercover!
See you're still in the driver's seat.
Come on, get on up
We're wild and we can't be tamed
And we're turnin' the floor
Into a zoo-ooh-ooh
Here we go! Here we go! Let's go!
Zootopia, let me hear ya!
We live in a crazy world
Caught up in a rat race
Concrete jungle life
Is sometimes a mad place
It's you and me together
At the end of a wild day
Don't keep it all bottled up
And release your energy
Only reason we are here is to celebrate
In a place where anyone can be anything
Hold on to this moment
Don't let it fade away
Baby, keep the music playin'
Come on, get on up
We're wild and we can't be tamed
And we're turnin' the floor
Into a zoo-ooh-ooh
Come on, keep it up
It's fun if you're down to play
And we're turnin' the floor
Into a zoo-ooh-ooh
Cats and lights. I know better.
A zoo-ooh-ooh
Come on, get on up
We're wild and we can't be tamed
And we're turnin' the floor
Into a zoo-ooh-ooh
And Mayor Winddancer has arrived,
star of the revenge trilogy,
The Neigh-sayer.
No pictures, please.
Come on. It's me.
And that, and that one, and then this one.
Mr. Lynxley, when will you begin
the Tundratown expansion?
-Come on, Dad.
-Have a wonderful time at the party.
It's fun if you're down to play
And we're turnin' the floor
Into a zoo-ooh-ooh
No snow.
This one's warmer.
A reptile in Tundratown might need that
to survive the cold.
Oh, my God. A viper!
A window wiper. Ja?
Back door ajar.
Anyone could have left it like that.
And you said, "Snoop a little,"
not break and enter--
Oh, God!
We were always going inside.
Got it. Same page means your page.
It's called a hustle, sweetheart.
You change out here. I get the van.
It's the Zootennial Gala.
A bunny comes prepared.
You know, I used to dream
of infiltrating a place like this.
You know, this is not your worst idea.
Wow, that was almost a compliment.
Your worst idea
is what you did with your ears.
All right.
Welcome to the Zootennial Gala,
featuring the original Lynxley Journal.
Why would a snake wanna steal
some old book anyway?
I don't know.
But no one is gonna steal it,
because we're here to protect it.
The journal is
in the reserved section. Okay.
Come on.
Slow down.
You want to fit in?
Commando is not gonna cut it.
It's not just the clothes, m'kay?
It is the vibe.
Good to see ya. Hey, real nice humps.
Is that real mink? This is real fox.
Get invited to a lot of these?
Invited? No.
But there's other reasons to hob knob.
Madam, excuse me. Is this yours?
Why, yes.
Well, allow me.
Clever fox.
There!
I don't think it has enough guards.
I'll get a closer look. Watch my six.
Bogo alert.
Cover's made of metal.
Gruffalo Buffalo has joined the mix.
Three o'clock.
-Excuse me. I am so sorry.
-Oh, no. Sorry.
Here, lemme just… Oh, nope.
That belongs to you. I apologize.
Oh, gosh. He hates me.
Here.
You're my hero.
Well, just like to be prepared
for any possible scenario.
Which is not a weird thing
to say at a party.
Well, I just mopped a spill
with that guy's tail, so…
Paw!
Pawbert. I am Pawbert. Hi.
Judy. I'm Judy Hopps.
What the pork?
Well, 'tis nice to meet you, Judy…
Wait. Judy Hopps? The Judy Hopps?
Are you working this?
I mean, you're clearly working it.
But are you actually working this?
No. Actually… Well, it's just a hunch.
Protecting that.
Good. I don't think it has enough guards.
That was my joke.
Yeah, and there's nothing here.
Let's call it a night.
Hopps?
Well, we should…
It was nice to meet you.
Yes, and you.
Bon appétit.
If, at any point tonight,
you choose to eat, bon appétit then.
You're supposed to be off stage, Pawbert.
Yeah, get off stage, Pawbert.
Wait, are you…
Yeah, I am a Lynxley.
Or, you know, I'm trying to be.
Now, Pawbert.
Come on, Papi.
-I got you, Pa. Don't you worry.
-No, I have him.
All right, let's get this thing started.
Welcome to the Zootennial Gala.
Hey, Hopps. I think I might actually…
I think I've got something.
Look at you all.
Good to see ya.
It is with great pleasure that I introduce
the third-generation visionary…
Carrots, can you hear me? I have a trail.
…who has continued the legacy
of our great city, Milton Lynxley.
-Thank you. Thank you very much.
-Carrots. Carrots.
What are you doing here?
Chief, she was right.
-You're done. You're both done.
-Wait. No, no.
My grandpa had a dream
to build a city for all animals.
Nick?
To truly be better together.
There's a snake!
Snake, snake, snake!
Go, bro, go.
I will remember you, zebra.
Judy. Judy!
I knew it!
Stop!
Please. You don't have to hurt him.
Hurt him?
Snakes never hurt anyone.
We aren't the bad guys.
They are.
And this journal holds the secret
that will prove it.
I have to prove it. Please.
This is our only chance
to set things right.
And when I do,
my family will finally be able
to come home.
-Oh, no!
-I am here.
Hopps and Wilde, dream team.
We got him. Or her.
Reptiles, it's, like, who knows?
The cops are right behind us.
Kill the snake.
We'll burn the journal.
If he wants it, it's dangerous.
And you two will file a report
that he attacked us,
and you will keep your mouths shut.
Step aside.
Put out the fire!
-Carrots, come on.
-Help me save him.
-Carrots, we need--
-Nick.
Cold! Cold!
No!
Chief.
He'll be okay.
Antivenom. He can be saved with antivenom.
-Hopps, what did you do?
-No, Hoggbottom.
They're helping the snake.
They're trying to kill the chief!
-Hoggbottom, no. Please.
-Backup! I need backup!
-My page. Let's go.
-Wait, wait, wait.
I need the journal and probably a sweater.
Cold.
-On the ground.
-Wait.
-Oi!
-Next time, we stay home?
Don't you move.
No. Stop them!
-Oi!
-Come on.
-Stop!
-Come on!
Stop!
Oh, God.
I really am just a dumb bunny.
Accident. Your words, not mine.
Put 'em in the trunk.
"Ter-roar" in Tundratown.
A fanging at the fiesta.
A howl-a at the gala as a venomous snake
attacks the founding family.
More shocking, the snake was aided
by embattled ZPD officers
Nicholas Wilde and Judy Hopps.
All three now suspects
in the tragic fanging
of Zootopia's chief of police
and considered extremely dangerous.
Chief Bogo… is dead.
Those are words I'm glad
I don't have to say.
I might have to soon.
The doctors are a little weirded out,
but what has happened tonight
was more than horseplay.
We…
We're gonna take that snake down.
And the fox and that rabbit!
Do you know how many mayors
they've already destroyed?
One, two… I got up to two.
Would you like to be "three"?
I want them gone.
But aren't there… laws?
I will say this once, Brian.
You will retrieve the journal
and bury them.
Or maybe I chose the wrong mayor.
Did I choose the wrong mayor?
Hey.
The phone is the first thing
they'll track.
Sorry. I have never been
on the run from the law before.
Yeah. Boy.
It's almost like we shouldn't
have gone to that gala, huh?
Okie doke. We already did it your way.
With Mr. Big, we do it mine.
This is where having a partner from
the underworld is really gonna pay off.
Raymond! And is that Kev…
Welcome to my warehouse.
Oh, my God, I love your dress.
Thank you.
Fru Fru and I are now equal partners
in the family business.
She brings wonderful ideas
for crime and for fashion
while I get more time to focus
on what matters most:
being grandpapa to my little Judith.
Kiss my ring.
-Kiss the stinking ring right now!
-You kiss it right now! Kiss it!
Nonno, you said we were gonna
make cement shoes for Mr. Weaselton.
That's my girl.
They grow up so fast.
-You shut your mouth, fox!
-You run your mouth too much!
Anyways, you're in trouble.
And we like one of yas,
so we're here to help.
New clothes. New identities.
Truck out of town leaves in an hour.
And your meter maid cart is taken care of.
I think you misunderstand.
We've been framed by the lynxes.
And an innocent snake needs…
Judy, the lynxes are killers,
and they have no honor.
And this Tundratown expansion
only makes them more dangerous.
Territorial animals will do anything
for more land.
So, if whatever you're tangled up in
threatens their plans, you're dead.
You don't fight the cats. You leave.
Sir, I know you're trying
to look out for us.
But we took an oath to protect this city.
And justice doesn't run.
On behalf of myself, "Rick Wilde,"
and "Miss Trudy Cabbagepatch,"
we thank you for your truck
to salvation and--
We cannot accept your offer.
We are helping that snake.
Boy, you're really
tossing that "we" around.
Snakes may have been framed
for the fanging of that tortoise.
Do you have any idea why?
Or how this book could prove it?
I wish I did.
But if it has to do with snakes,
your best bet is talking to a reptile.
Do you know any?
Almost no one does.
They keep to themselves,
hide out in Marsh Market.
But you can still find 'em.
You just need a reptile expert.
Someone local who knows where to go.
Lucky for you, I met someone.
She runs a podcast!
No, no. Trudy Cabbagepatch,
Rick Wilde says no.
Oh, yeah!
If Hopps and Wilde are on the lam,
subtle sleuthin' 'tis my jam.
Mind the splinters.
You called the right beaver.
If you wanna talk to a reptile,
I am your gal.
Also, if you need to talk to a jackalope,
which are real, Mom!
Excuse us. Team meeting.
Vetoing the beave.
New vote: All in favor
of "Truck to Being Alive
and Laying Low
Till This Blows Over-ville"? I mean…
Hopps and Wilde do not bail on a case.
But she's crazy.
Probably lead poisoning
from eating too many pencils.
Do you know a reptile who can
tell us the hidden secret in here,
or why the lynxes framed the snakes?
Twenty-four hours. Sunrise tomorrow.
If we strike out, then we go into hiding,
and "Judy Cabbagepatch" it is.
It's "Trudy" Cabbagepatch,
and the safe word is "coconut."
In the darkness of a dank underpass,
they stepped into the vehicle,
not realizing their lives
were about to change.
Because we're gonna meet a reptile?
Because you're about to be best buds
with Nibbles Maplestick!
Takes two to tango,
but a threesome to be somethin'.
Let's find you a reptile
and romp the swamp.
Breathe it in!
Now, if any reptile would know
the secret of that book
and why the snake wants it...
Hey, Johnny!
Oh, no!
...it's my old lizard friend, Jesús.
Why would a lizard hide here?
Well, when Zootopia was founded,
the whole neighborhood got cut off
from the rest of the town.
Kinda on our own here.
Yeah, that's probably why
reptiles like it.
They can just do their thing.
Plus, it's the only place in town
you can get away with
wearing a shirt and no pants.
Loving tour time with Woodchuckles.
Great call.
-We need her.
-Oh, yeah. Like a hole in the head.
Bad timing.
Okay, to get to Jesús's hideout,
we gotta take a ferry.
Just let me handle the locals.
Water folk tend to be
a little standoffish around landies.
Well, I've been hustling the streets
since I was 12.
I think I can handle a juggling seal.
Sea lion.
He's not from around here.
But coin's a coin.
No. Change is a choking hazard.
Well, honest mistake.
Do not do that!
Let's let Nibbles handle this.
Thank you, Judith.
Conversing with these
beautiful sea creatures
is like talking to anyone
a little different.
Just takes open
and respectful communication.
-Heya, bub.
-Hey, bub.
-Heya, bub, hey.
-Hey, bub, heya.
-Bubba, bubba, bubba.
-Heya, bub.
-Hey, bub. Hey, bub, bub.
-Heya, bub. Bubby, bub.
-Hey, bub. Hey, bub. Hey, ho.
-Heya, bub, bub.
-Hey, bub.
Seen Jesús?
Yup.
And now we leave town.
Thank you for this.
Happy anniversary.
It's your anniversary?
This is the night
It's a beautiful night
And we call it bella notte
How are we gonna find them now?
Thanks, seal.
Friend. No, no, no!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry!
Just a little farther.
Jesús and all the answers you'll ever need
are right here at the end of this
very scary, dark hallway.
Boy, this is so much better than
sitting on a beach on Outback Island,
sipping piña koalas.
We are not skipping town when there is
an innocent snake out there who needs us.
He's got help: his motorcycle buddy.
You are acting weird.
What is your problem?
Well, A, you railroaded me.
And B,
if you must know,
I have an aversion to reptiles.
What?
Is my discomfort hilarious to you?
No, you're... I'm sorry.
You're right, we are partners.
And whenever I'm uncomfortable, you are
always very considerate of my feelings.
Look out! Snake skin!
I'm slipping! I'm slipping! Hold the rail!
-I'm holding the rail.
-Hold it. Hold it.
-Stop pulling my ears!
-Hold the rail.
Never pull a bunny's ears!
-Never pull a bunny's ears!
I think the real mystery
is how you two ever solved anything.
Anyhoo, let's see what Jesús has to say
about your journal.
And if he offers you food, accept.
Declining is a sign of disrespect,
to all of them.
"All of them"?
Order up.
Hey, another drink.
So warm.
Whoops.
No!
Keep it.
Jesús!
Allow me to introduce my friends.
This is Judith and Nicholas.
They are wanted fugitives
investigating a snake mystery
and trying not to get murdered.
May we sit?
Okay.
I'm good, but these guys look hungry.
Thank you for meeting with us.
We believe snakes were framed
for something in this journal,
-perhaps pertaining to...
-Eat first, talk second.
Hey, guys. They ate it!
Look at their faces.
I don't eat grubs.
Hermano, get me a scone!
Okay, okay.
Metal cover.
And what does that mean?
It means
it's fancy.
It also means
the secret you're looking for
is probably right on the cover.
Somehow vipers can see things
in the metal,
even under the paint.
This is Ebenezer Lynxley's original
journal for the weather walls.
Why would he hide a secret for a snake?
I don't know.
But it must have been big,
'cause a tortoise died for it.
I am guessing that it was a slow death.
The fanging didn't just change
how folks saw snakes.
No mammals trusted any reptile after that.
That's why we all left.
And that's when the Lynxleys
expanded Tundratown the first time.
And it's happening again.
The expansion is going here.
Marsh Market will be buried in snow.
We'll all get pushed out.
Those lynxes will get more land,
and there's no way to stop 'em.
What if the secret hidden in here could?
Then I would say
holding it puts the two of you
in grave danger.
They tracked you?
Whoops.
It's the ZPD!
Run!
Follow me. Come on!
Wait. Why are you helping us?
You two saved the city once.
I reckon you can save it again.
And when you do,
maybe everyone will see
we ain't that different.
-Freeze!
-Yeah, freeze!
I'm really sorry. But this is
my family's only chance to come home.
Wait. We wanna help.
Wait. Wait.
Come back!
There's no path. Take the docks!
Wha-- Carrots!
Wait! We believe you!
Nick! Come on! Come on!
Grab it!
Hey!
I got eyes on them.
They're heading for the tubes!
In pursuit.
Hey, bubba.
-Hey, bub.
Go!
Bub-bye.
-Bub-bye.
Bub-bye. Bye.
-Hey, bub.
-Bub-bye.
Pro tip! If he goes for the red line,
do not follow!
You will run out of air!
Good luck! I love you!
Sorry.
Cannonball!
That's a red line. Red line!
You're going to run out of air!
Coconut! Coconut!
Anything you need, I got 'em.
Sequels, prequels, requels.
Who says the industry's
going down the tubes?
Are you okay?
Yeah. Yes.
You?
I... Well, I've...
I feel like some...
some "sorries" may be in order.
Nick, it's okay.
I know you didn't want to
lose him on purpose.
Not me sorry. No, no.
You sorry.
Well, now we kinda have no way
to find him or stop the lynxes,
so agree to disagree.
But...
we are alive.
So if we can't find him, that's great.
What we can find is a truck out of here.
Box of old matches. Helpful.
Trudy Cabbagepatch, leaving town.
We're done.
Yodelayheehoo!
Dis is veird place for you to be.
Ja, very veird.
Zey fell out of ze tube.
Okay, ve vill call police to help!
Nope! No, no, we're fine.
Yep, we were just leaving town.
Actually, do you happen to know
where this tube goes?
-Copenhoofen.
-Ja, ist Copenhoofen.
Got it. Thank y--
You chew too much. This is not okay!
Where did...
Where did you find these flowers?
The Liebenflower?
Ze tippity-top of ze mountain.
Zis is ze only place zey grow.
Oh, boy.
Is...
Is there anything else up there?
-Nope, there sure isn't.
-Ja.
Old Honeymoon Lodge.
But is closed for long time.
Was hideout for snakes.
Honeymoon Lodge.
How... How do you reach it?
Tourists take ze tram from Copenhoofen,
but ze rope is faster.
Good luck!
Have fun at ze Honeymoon Lodge!
Thank you!
What does the secret have to do
with the reptiles leaving town?
How did it get hidden in the journal
in the first place?
Will you slow down?
How long do you think it's going to be
before Hoggbottom and the ZPD
figure out where we are?
If anything, we should be going faster.
As I always say...
I really am just a dumb bunny.
Nick...
I-- I-- I really am--
just-- dumb-- dumb-- dumb bunny.
Just dumb-- dumb-- dumb bunny.
This was a gift
to symbolize our partnership,
and it is not appropriate for this moment.
Oh, no, I was just hoping
to jot down some ideas
for what we will put on our tombstones.
I'll start. "His partner did it."
What happened to you that you can't
just have a normal conversation?
I will save that for my therapy animal.
-Yeah, you need a therapy animal.
-Oh, yeah.
Well, you need a herd of therapy animals.
Yeah. You need a whole migration
of therapy animals.
Carrots?
Hey, Carrots?
Carrots!
There was a whole reptile neighborhood.
Their home...
The lynxes just erased it.
This is what they do.
We have to go.
They push animals out with lies
so they can have more.
We gotta go. Carrots, we gotta go!
-That's what the snake's trying to prove.
-The ZPD is here.
What?
No one will believe us. Not without proof.
Leave it.
They aren't gonna just arrest us.
The lynxes want us dead.
We need it to solve the case.
-Judy, just...
-We have to solve the case.
-Nick...
-I don't care about the case!
Judy, it's not worth dying for.
The world will never be a better place
if no one is brave enough
to do the right thing.
The world is what it is, Carrots,
and sometimes being a hero...
it just doesn't make a difference.
I think...
I think maybe...
maybe we...
are different.
Oh, my gosh,
I think I just took out a cop.
Sorry, sir!
-Pawbert?
-Yeah. It's... you know...
-We're the good guys!
-I told you she's helping.
Come with us.
We have the fox. We have the fox!
They already have your partner.
They can't get you too.
Please. We can stop my family.
Judy!
No, no, no!
I got you.
All right. Here we go.
What?
You're not dead!
She's not dead!
Sorry, sorry.
I just got my motorcycle license.
Nick?
They...
They caught him.
But out here, no one's gonna catch us.
Mayor Winddancer.
Where's the bunny?
I don't know.
But, you know, she's a rabbit.
So maybe you can pull her out of your hat.
I'm not wearing a hat.
He's messing with you, sir.
I knew that. Get him out of here.
No.
Where are they, Mr. Wilde?
Begin the expansion.
Freeze Marsh Market.
-Flush everyone out.
-What? No, you can't--
Water folk, like foxes,
are lesser mammals.
If I say they helped a dangerous snake,
no one will care what we do.
You're going to a dark cell, Mr. Wilde.
Just long enough to read the headline
of your partner's demise.
You should've left town
when you had the chance.
Dad.
Fur from whoever's helping
the bunny and the snake.
Find Pawbert.
Almost to me hideout.
Snake in the hole.
Yeah, yeah.
We shall succeed, Judy Hopps.
We'll stop the Lynxleys
and save your partner.
I'm sorry. You are...
Gary. Gary the Snake.
And your last name?
De'Snake.
Everything is gonna be okay.
Teaming up with you is very exciting.
Don't worry about my fang.
I got my own antivenom pen.
Stops the toxin.
Stab me straight into the heart.
Welcome to my oasis,
away from my evil family.
I like to come here, just kind of veg out.
-Get with all my cat stuff.
-Wow.
-No! That's actually vintage.
-Awesome.
No! If you could just not.
No! No, please don't.
-Wow! Mammals get the best stuff.
-Oh, my gosh. No.
-What's this do?
-Wait, not that.
Turn it off. Turn it off. Turn it off.
Turn it off. Turn it off.
So, we should probably get to the journal.
How did you become partners?
When I found out the journal was going
to be on display at the Gala,
I sent his family an anonymous letter
asking to see it.
Luckily, they make Pawbert work
in the mail room, so he read it first.
I got him smuggled in from overseas.
Seven days in a crate.
But if I fix things for my family,
it'll be worth it.
Then we'll fix things
for your partner too.
Hey.
I know coming with us was hard,
but we're gonna help your partner,
the same way we're gonna help the city.
We stop my family
and show everyone the truth.
Are you ready?
Light the fire.
How much do you know?
Well, that his family was framed,
and there's some secret
hidden in the metal cover
that only a snake can see.
Not just any snake,
a heat-sensing pit viper.
All it takes is a little warmth.
I just... I don't understand.
Why would your great-grandfather
hide a secret for a snake?
He didn't.
I...
It wasn't his journal.
That's the secret.
Zootopia wasn't created by a mammal.
It was created by a snake.
Gary's great-grandmother.
She wanted to make the city a place
where all animals felt welcome.
So she invented her weather walls
to help everyone.
She just needed an investor.
A partner.
But when my great-grandfather
saw what her idea could be worth...
he plotted to steal her plans for himself.
So he committed a murder...
his own maid...
and framed Gary's great-grandmother.
And because she was a snake
everyone believed his lie.
Soon, no reptiles were welcome.
And over time,
my great-grandfather
buried the reptile neighborhood in snow.
And he died believing no one
could ever uncover his crimes.
But...
he was wrong.
Her original patent was saved.
That's what you're looking for.
She hid it in her home.
Find her home, find her patent.
We just didn't know
where her home was buried
until now.
My family's land?
But under all that snow,
how are we gonna find it?
Wait.
Clock tower.
Her neighborhood, the reptile
neighborhood, had a clock tower.
It lights up like a beacon. If it wasn't
fully buried, maybe we could see it.
Follow it to her home.
Except my great-grandfather
turned off the power.
But we have the plans that show us
how to turn it back on.
The power switch to her whole neighborhood
was in the original control room.
All right!
And where is that?
Inside the oldest wall of the city.
The Desert Tundratown weather wall.
We get inside, turn on that switch,
light the clock tower,
-we find her house.
-We find her patent.
And my family is finally coming home.
We will succeed, Judy Hopps.
We shall succeed!
I found him.
Get me Hoggbottom.
It's Nicholas Wilde. Big-time cop, huh?
I'll see you at the lunch table.
I'm gonna tie your tail in a knot.
-Hoggbottom--
-What are you looking at, butthead?
This is a mistake.
It's a setup. It's the lynxes.
Listen to me. Please.
I know we have had our differences, right?
But I've always respected you--
You don't respect anyone.
Phone. It's Milton Lynxley.
He's got the rabbit's location.
Whatever he says, it's a lie, Hoggbottom.
Hoggbottom, listen to me!
Oh, God.
Nicholas Wilde!
What are the chances?
You know, this is my first time in prison,
and I gotta say,
their food is on point.
How are you even here?
Destiny.
Plus an arrest.
But it looks like Judith got away.
Was that decision mutual?
Sensing trouble in paradise.
Wanna talk about it?
What I want is to get out of here.
Right, your big plan.
Lay low on Outback Island
sipping piña koalas.
Except you can't trust koalas,
'cause they got four thumbs.
Did a whole episode about it
on my podcast.
It was called "They Got Four Thumbs."
But you know what?
At least they ain't platypuses.
Wait. Can you just...
Can you please just let me concentrate?
Roger that.
Just talk to me, dude!
What's the last thing she said to you?
She...
She said maybe we are too different.
And what did you say before that?
I said the case isn't worth dying for.
Like...
like, you know, as in it isn't
worth her dying for because...
because solitary animals like me
don't have real friends.
And I... I don't want to lose her.
So, I just...
I don't know how to say that.
You know what, bud? I think you just did.
Wait, how did you do that?
Well, I opened my arms,
put them around you and then I squeezed.
It's called a hug. Do foxes not have hugs?
The lock. Yeah, that's Beave 101.
The rabbit's in Desert Dunes. Roll out!
Hit it. Roll out!
Your partner needs you,
and Nibbles Maplestick
is gonna get you to her.
Hey! It's the fox dad! And the woodchuck!
Woodchuck? I'm a beaver!
Call me that again--
-Oops.
-Okay, go! We gotta go! Here we go!
Get back here!
Hello, Nicholas.
I hope you like my new home.
I wove it with my own wool.
Jump scare!
Adios!
We're free!
Wheels. We need wheels. No, no.
No, no, no, no.
I am sorry.
I do not think we can get to Judy
in time to help.
Unless...
you happen to know the fastest driver
in the history of Zootopia.
Hey, Flash, Flash Hundred Yard Dash.
Partner's in trouble.
Need to get across town, ignore the laws.
No...
problem.
Let's hit it.
Hey.
-Glad you're here.
-I gotta tell ya,
I'm not convinced
a sloth is our most reliable--
Oh, yeah!
To turn on the clock tower
and light the way to your great-grandma's
home so we can find her patent,
we need to reach the power control room
through here.
-We have to move quickly or we're never--
-We shall succeed, Judy Hopps.
Look, Gary, if we don't over-prepare,
we're underprepared and I don't...
My family's been trying to prove we're not
what everyone thinks for a hundred years.
But even this close,
they'd never want me to put
the weight of the world on my shoulders.
Because I don't have any shoulders.
We shall succeed.
I got you, rabbit.
I cannot help Judy
if I don't know where she is,
which is why I need you to get
on Paul's computer and track Hoggbottom.
You are an escaped fugitive.
I could get fired for even talking to you.
They're gonna put her to sleep! Do it!
Okay!
Did you try restarting it?
Have you tried not being an idiot?
Hey, Paul. I got you some donuts.
-Oh, no!
-Thanks, Clawhauser.
Clawhauser! Location!
Oh, no.
I think we're gonna
have to go through the festival.
Festival?
The phone's the first thing they track.
Go! Go!
-Clawhauser!
-I am working on it.
-I got it!
-Great, great, great. Now--
No!
What festival is this?
Yeah!
Move, move, move!
-Come on!
-Go, go, go!
We are with you, Judy Hopps.
We meet again, Zebra.
Here come the horns!
She's going for the door.
She's going for the door!
Clawhauser, we're out of time.
I got it!
Desert Tundratown weather wall
access door.
access door. Hurry!
-What is in that wall?
-Power control room.
But for, like,
some old part of Tundratown.
I know what they're doing.
They'll ruin us!
No more tranquilizers. Put them down.
-Sir.
-Put them down. Now!
Take the shot.
Take the shot! Do it!
Judy!
-Snake!
-Power control room?
Five flights up. Come on, hurry!
That is a lot of stairs.
Way to hustle, bud, I love ya! I owe ya!
It's turning on. It's turning on!
Nibbles?
Nibbles!
Snake!
Cold!
It's jammed.
Don't worry about me. Find the switch.
No, no, no, no. Not these.
It would be… older.
Can you see it?
Did we turn on the clock tower?
There!
It's there!
We did it?
We can find the original patent?
Nick?
The door… It's locked…
How did it lock?
Nibbles? Open it.
Nibbles!
Dang door stuck on me.
Sorry.
Last case there was kind of a twist.
I know.
Oh, my gosh. I really…
My heart is pounding.
I thought you knew. I thought you knew.
Sorry, partner.
Hate to leave you out in the cold,
but I'm gonna.
Please don't be mad at me.
But, I mean, you get it.
We've always been
on the same page. Me and you!
Underdogs, right?
You gotta prove you're as good
as everyone else.
That you belong.
I know, it's messed up,
but this is my chance.
I have to take it.
'Cause when I get
to his great-grandma's home,
and I burn the original patent,
I'll finally be something in my family.
And I'll finally belong too.
Judy?
Ruh-roh.
Carrots?
No loose ends.
Bye, partner.
Bye, Judy Hopps.
Pawbert. Please.
You can be different than your family.
I don't want to be different.
Nick…
Judy?
Nibbles, do you see her?
No, nothing yet.
Judy.
Nick.
Ni…
We shall succeed,
Judy Hopps.
It's okay. Judy sent me.
She needs to find Nick.
Yep. Should've seen that coming.
Judy?
Nick.
We… shall… succeed.
Judy…
I can't move.
And you're too cold to help.
And he's gonna…
Nick's gonna…
Judy…
The world was never meant to be
on one animal's shoulders.
That's why my great-grandma wanted
Zootopia to be for everyone.
So, we could all help each other.
I didn't help.
You did.
You chose to help me
and became my best warm-blooded friend.
Very warm.
Permission to hug?
We're gonna save you and save your friend.
Judy!
Hey, he's gonna eat that rabbit!
No, wait! I'm saving her!
I'm gonna get her the anti-pen.
Where is she?
She… She didn't make it.
But with snake bites, you go fast.
You'll see.
No!
She's gone, Nick. Just get it over with!
You're done.
Know when to quit!
Anti-venom!
You can save her with the anti-venom!
Throw me the bag!
Judy!
Leave it! You're gonna kill us both.
It's not worth dying for.
Agree to disagree.
Stab me straight into the heart.
-I was trying to get to you, and…
-I thought… He told me that you…
-I saw you…
-…that you were…
I'll help your friend.
Okay, I don't care that we're different.
You know? I…
What I care about is you.
I care about you.
Okay?
And I didn't say it.
I should've said it.
But I didn't
because…
Well,
'cause I am an emotionally
insecure source of your discomfort,
who's not good at expressing his feelings.
Probably because I've been on my own
my whole life.
It's not an excuse. It's just…
It's why instead of telling you
that you're the best thing
that ever happened to me,
I make jokes about your ears.
And I tell you that you try too hard,
when, you know, the truth is
I just don't want you to get hurt.
Because…
Because no one else in the world
matters more to me than you do.
I… I do try too hard because deep down
I'm afraid that I am
what everyone thinks I am.
And I suppress my discomfort
because I'm worried it makes me look weak,
and I wanna be strong,
and I think I'm failing all the time.
And I only take what you say personally
because you're the only one in my life
who ever believed in me,
even when I don't even believe in myself.
And I should have told you that.
No one else in the world matters to me
more than you do either.
I have unresolved childhood trauma
that I refuse to discuss
because being vulnerable scares me.
I make dangerous choices because
I have an unhealthy bunny hero complex.
And I didn't join the ZPD
because I wanted to be a cop.
I joined because I always wanted
to be part of a pack.
And the thought of losing you
scares me because…
because you're my pack.
I should never have left you,
and I do need a herd of therapy animals.
And I should have told you that
you are the only partner I would ever want
because you're my fluffle.
That's a bunch of rabbits.
Now that is what we call an overshare.
I'm alive by the way. I made it.
Also that guy is still alive.
Hey! Hey! Thief!
He's gonna get to
the lost reptile neighborhood,
find Gary's great-grandma's
patent and destroy it.
Yeah, I've got no idea what that means,
or who Gary is, but let's go!
-Hopps and Wilde?
-Wilde and Hopps.
And Nibbles and Gary!
He's Gary.
Thank you. It's for the snake.
He's cold. No fur on him.
-Hey! Why you little…
-Bye now.
-You! You don't belong in this family!
-Dad! Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
-Dad--
-You will never belong in this family!
Wait, wait, wait! I wasn't working
with them. I was helping us.
I know where
the reptile neighborhood is buried.
Where to find the real patent that proves
that snakes invented the walls.
I'm going to destroy it, for the family.
For you, Daddy.
You want to keep your job,
you say nothing.
You!
Maybe you are a Lynxley.
Take me to the patent.
Takes a threesome to be somethin',
but a four-way to bust your doorway.
Get to the patent! Destroy it!
Go! We got this.
Hey, whiskers,
you're done hurtin' muh city.
Uh-oh. Tides have turned.
Hey, Brian Winddancer!
You want to be a hero,
or just play one on TV?
Come on.
Okay, I go left, and you go right?
Yeah.
Or…
You are a horrible driver.
Yes, I am.
I'm gonna jump!
Zoogetherness.
No, never mind. Forget I said it.
Here we go.
Matches, matches, matches, matches.
Bunnies, we're burrowers.
Rabbit kick.
I'll destroy the patent, that town
and everything in it.
And a dirtbag fox and a dumb bunny
will never stand in my way.
She's not a dumb bunny,
and you're forgetting one thing.
What's that?
We're friends with a snake.
Howdy, partner.
Heads up!
-Daddy!
-Daddy's busy.
Brian! Go!
You say, "Justice is dead."
I say, "Neigh!"
-Here, kitty, kitty.
-No!
It's called an arrest, sweetheart.
Boom.
No one will believe you over us.
We've always been better than you.
And we always will be.
Nothing you do matters.
Well, it matters to him.
Shall we?
One long sock.
I'm gonna burn it all to the ground!
I'm a real Lynxley!
That'll do, pig. That'll do.
Astonishing news today after
officers Judy Hopps and Nicholas Wilde,
along with a pit viper and a beaver,
foiled another major conspiracy
by revealing the true inventor
of the city's weather walls
was a snake.
While the now disgraced Lynxley family
were revealed to have stolen
the original plans
and covered it up for decades.
You have not heard the last of Milton…
Their Tundratown expansion,
now officially canceled.
Some are calling you the dream team.
How did you do it?
Well, there's a lot of
different animals out there.
And sometimes,
we start to look at all the little reasons
that we're not the same.
And it makes us worry.
But maybe if we just talked to each other,
if we just tried
to understand one another,
we would see that our differences
don't really make any difference
at all.
Maybe we'd even see
that what makes me me and you you,
can make us even stronger.
And with hard work,
you're gonna get to that by year two!
Yeah.
-Zebros.
-Actually, my name is Gene.
My name is also Gene.
-Zebros!
He did it!
Kids, get off the snake.
Hi. How is everybody doing?
One sec!
This is my family.
Permission to hug?
Thank you.
Hey, I got you something.
Love you, partner.
But I am still me,
so I'm only saying it once a decade.
Love you, partner.
I'm gonna need that back.
I'll give it back to you
after our next case.
There's gonna be another case, huh?
Of course.
Because, when you broke out of jail,
you also released
200 highly dangerous prisoners.
Worth it.
Any idea where you want to start?
One-way ticket to Outback Island, please.
First class.
Very nice.
And remember,
if you're happy with our service,
please be sure to leave us four thumbs up.
I will.
Hopps and Wilde?
Wilde and Cabbagepatch.
Zootopia, vamos!
Burning Mammal, let's go!
Come on, get on up
We're wild and we can't be tamed
And we're turnin' the floor
Into a zoo-ooh-ooh
We live in a crazy world
Caught up in a rat race
Concrete jungle life
Is sometimes a mad place
It's you and me together
At the end of a wild day
Don't keep it all bottled up
And release your energy
Only reason we are here
Is to celebrate
In a place where anyone
Can be anything
Hold on to this moment
Don't let it fade away
Baby, keep the music playin'
Come on, get on up
We're wild and we can't be tamed
And we're turnin' the floor
Into a zoo-ooh-ooh
Come on, keep it up
It's fun if you're down to play
And we're turnin' the floor
Into a zoo-ooh-ooh
Zoo-ooh-ooh
A zoo-ooh-ooh
We live in a heated time
No chance to cool down
Continuously confined
And what do we do now?
It's all about finding love
Sometimes hard to come by
But when it comes to us
It's always a good time
Only reason we are here
Is to celebrate
In a place where anyone
Can be anything
Hold on to this moment
Don't let it fade away
Baby, keep the music playin'
Come on, get on up
We're wild and we can't be tamed
And we're turnin' the floor
Into a zoo-ooh-ooh
Come on, keep it up
It's fun if you're down to play
And we're turnin' the floor
Into a zoo-ooh-ooh
A zoo-ooh-ooh
Zoo-ooh-ooh
I'll take you higher
We can't be tamed
Baby, I'll take you higher
I'll take you higher
And we can't be tamed
Baby, I'll take you higher
Es una fiesta que sube como la espuma
Yo por ti iré hasta la luna
De ida y vuelta
Es una fiesta que sube como la espuma
Yo por ti iré hasta la luna
De ida y vuelta
Come on, get on up
We're wild and we can't be tamed
And we're turnin' the floor
Into a zoo-ooh-ooh
Come on, keep it up
It's fun if you're down to play
And we're turnin' the floor
Into a zoo-ooh-ooh
Come on, get on up
We're wild and we can't be tamed
And we're turnin' the floor
Into a zoo-ooh-ooh
Come on, keep it up
It's fun if you're down to play
And we're turnin' the floor
Into a zoo-ooh-ooh
Love you, partner.
Hey, bunny.
Ya gonna keep playing that all night?
Leave her alone, she's proud of herself,
but still seeks external validation.
-Shut up!
-You shut up!
You shut up!
Hey, bunny, what's next for you two?
We're investigating a rabbit
who strangled her neighbors.
You offended her.
-You offended her!
-Shut up.
-Good night!
-You shut up.